JFROCK KALALA

801 Seminole Creek CT, Lexington, KY 40511 · 7573580771

jerockkalala@gmail.com - · @jerock_kalala - www.github.com/jerockkalala

Diligent IT Support providing technical support for various Microsoft operating systems, and computer hardware. Balance priorities while quickly solving issues to strengthen business processes and performance. Self-motivated problem solver with 5+ years of experience using content management and multiple software including Delta, Amplitude, Socrates, and Gravis. Show development in my skills and knowledge to help clients achieve growth and success.

EXPERIENCE

02/2022 - PRESENT

DESKTOP SUPPORT TECH, WORLDWIDE TECHSERVICES LEXINGTON, KY

- Support Windows desktops, laptops, phones, and printers on site, via phone, chat, or email
- Perform troubleshooting and repair activities typically associate in an end-user environment
- Basic administration (move/add/delete) of computers, users, and groups in Active Directory
- Take ownership of trouble tickets, working and tracking issues to resolution
- Create, assign priority, analyze, & provide prompt resolutions to tickets
- Provide technical support to end-users through remote tools
- Image Desktop/Laptop for deployment, and install multiple software, OS included
- Perform all assigned desk-side support activity

01/2017 - 08/2022

PROBLEM SOLVER, AMAZON FULFILLMENT CENTER LEX2 | LEXINGTON, KY, US

- Assisting co-workers to resolve computer hardware, software, and process issues.
- Interact with customer database to find order issues and submit tickets as needed.
- Process customer returned orders to detect and escalate any fraud.
- Identify, and update products record to reflect hazardous or nonhazardous status of items.
- Reconcile daily database report of all pending orders.

02/2013 - 10/2016

IT SUPPORT/EXPLOITATION, BIAC (INTERNATIONAL BANK FOR AFRICA), KINSHASA, DRC

- Manipulate database, ensure daily data backup, daily Batch processing.
- Providing support to resolve technical issues to 1003+ users remotely and/or in person.
- Install patches on the main business software (Amplitude).
- Build and install desktop computers (Windows operating system and other Software).
- Maintain and troubleshoot computer hardware and software issues

EDUCATION

2023 -BACHELOR OF SCIENCE in Data Science, BELLEVUE UNIVERSITY, BELLEVUE, NE

2021 - ASSOCIATE IN APPLIED SCIENCE in **Computer Information Technology – Informatics**, BLUEGRASS COMMUNITY AND TECHNICAL COLLEGE, LEXINGTON, KY

2012 - BACHELOR OF SCIENCE in Math and Computer Science, UNIVERSITY OF KINSHASA, DRC

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Software

 Tableau, Power BI, installation and debugging (Windows OS, MS Office, antivirus, etc.), Active Directory
- Networks LAN/WAN technology, TCP/IP
- Programming —Python, R basics, JAVA, SQL, HTML & CSS basics, Web Scraping
- Machine Learning · NLP · TensorFlow
- Hardware assembly desktop/Laptop, maintenance, peripherals, Printers, Drivers, troubleshooting

GENERAL SKILLS

- Positive attitude
- Problem-solving
- Teamwork and attention to details
- Self-motivated able to work under pressure
- Dedicated work ethic
- Communication

LANGUAGES

- English
- French
- Swahili